Guide to the Kate Felton Elkins Collection, 1775-1927
Department of Special Collections
Kate Felton Elkins Collection,
1775-1927
Special Collections M0125
Elkins, Kate Felton.
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Kate Felton Elkins, 1934.
Scope and Content
Miscellaneous scrapbooks on musical, theatrical and literary subjects. Includes letters, programs, playbills, clippings, printed articles, prints and photographs. One bound volume, Dramatic, has twentieth century letters written to Felton Elkins. ca. 1775-1927.
Container List
- DRAMATIC - bound leather book containing autograph and signed letters by 19th and early 20th century theater personalities and others. Also contains old playbills, printed articles, prints and photographs. (Volume 1 (Vol.))
  note complete - see attachment
  - 1. Elkins, Felton Broomhall, 1889- (Page 1)
    - to Mrs. K. F. Neilson, Sept. 30, 1925with cover., T.L.S.
  - 2. Garrick, David, 1716-1779 (Page 14)
    - A.L., fragment, n.d.
  - 3. Corri, Domenico (Page 17)
    - to Mr. Peake, Nov. 28, 1807., A.L.S.
  - 4. Kemble, Charles, 1775-1854 Goodwin, William N. (Page 19)
    - Signatures on articles of agreement, Sept. 3, 1822.
  - 5. Ravel, Gabriel (Page 28)
    - to Mr. Sefton, Oct. 9, 1847., A.L.S.
  - 6. Smith, Solomon Franklin, 1801-1869 (Page 29)
    - to Carey and Hart, Sept. 17 1845., A.L.S.
  - 7. Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893 Autograph. (Page 32)
  - 8. Bishop, Charles B. (Page 33)
    - Signature on articles of agreement with H.C. Jarrett and H.D. Palmer, March 26, 1875.
  - 9. Barrett, Lawrence, 1837- Autograph. (Page 34)
  - 10. Bishop, Charles B. (Page 37)
    - Signature on articles of agreement with Rich and Stetson, Dec. 10, 1874.
  - 11. McCullough, John E., 1832- Autograph. (Page 40)
  - 12. Forrest, Edwin, 1806-1872 (Page 41)
    - to H.H. Clements, Feb. 14, 1855., A.L.S.
  - 13. Keene, [Laura?] Autograph. (Page 45)
  - 14. Covent, Byron (Page 47)
    - Telegram to E.A. Sothern
  - 15. Jefferson, Joseph Autograph. on a card (Page 50)
  - 16. Irving, (John) Henry (B.), 1838-1905 (Page 52)
    - to unknown [Aug.] 30, 1893., A.N.S.
  - 17. Modjeska, Helena, ca. 1843- Autograph. (Page 57)
  - 18. Drew, John Autograph. (Page 58)
  - 19. Rehan, Ada Autograph (Page 58)
  - 20. Neilson, Lilian Adelaide, 1850-1880 Autograph theater pass (Page 70)
  - 21. Cressy, John D. (Page 73)
    - to Directors of the American Theater, ALS
  - 22. Patti, Carlotta and Joseph Hermanns Autographs. (Page 32)
  - 23. P[atti], A[delina], 1843-1919 (Page 33)
    - to Dear friend, Aug. 31., A.L.S.
  - 24. Jefferson, Joseph Autograph. (Page 87)
  - 25. Booth, Edwin Autograph. (Page 87)
  - 26. Sothern, E.A. Autograph. (Page 88)
  - 27. Kendal, W. H. Autograph. (Page 90)
  - 28. Kendal, Madge Autograph (Page 90)
  - 29. Tree, Sir Herbert Beerbohm (Page 91)
    - to R.W. Welch, Nov. 26, 1903., T.L.S.
  - 30. Langtry, Lillie Autograph. (Page 91)
  - 31. Walsh, Blanche Autograph. (Page 92)
  - 32. Irving, Isabel Autograph (Page 92)
  - 33. Allen, Viola Autograph (Page 92)
  - 34. Burgess, Neil, 1846-1910 (Page 93)
    - to Friend Francis, A.L.S.
  - 35. Forbes-Robertson, Johnston, 1853-1937 (Page 94)
    - to Thomas D. Osborne, March 5, 1916., T.L.S.
  - 36. Forbes-Robertson, Gertrude (Page 95)
    - to Dear Sir, Nov. 22, 1909., A.L.S.
  - 37. Adams, Maude, 1872- (Page 96)
    - to [Edward] Freiberger, May 15, 1897., A.L.S.
  - 38. Barrie, Sir James Mathew, 1860-1937 (Page 97)
    - to?, Dec. 11., A.L.S.
  - 39. James, Louis and? Warde Autographs. (Page 99)
  - 40. Loftus, Cecilia, 1876- (Page 99)
    - to Miss Welch, July 1907., A.L.S.
  - 41. Irwin, May, 1862- (Page 99)
    - to George Leon Varney, Sept. 16, 1900., A.L.S.
  - 42. Elliott, Maxine Autographed photo. (Page 101)
  - 43. Marlowe, Julia, 1870- (Page 102)
    - to Mr. Carr, May 10, 1910and cvr., A.L.S.
  - 44. Mantell, R.B. Autograph. (Page 103)
  - 45. Trevelyan, Hilda, 1880 (Page 103)
    - to Mrs. Caley, Oct. 10, 1906., A.L.S.
  - 46. [Kelcey], Herbert Autograph. (Page 103)
  - 47. Erskine, James Autograph. (Page 104)
  - 48. Salvini, Thomas Autograph. (Page 104)
  - 49. Wright, Haidee, 1868- (Page 105)
    - to Dr. Waddell., A.L.S.
  - 50. Thompson, Lydia Autograph. (Page 105)
  - 51. Schildkraut, Joseph, 1895- (Page 106 & 107)
    - to [John] Howell, June 29, 1923with cvr., A.L.S.
  - 52. Housman, Lawrence, 1867- (Page 108)
    - to Dear Carr, Sept. 23, 1902., A.L.S.
  - 53. MacKaye, Percy, 1875- (Page 108)
    - to [Lewis] Lesley, Jan. 15, 1915., A.L.S.
  - 54. Winter, William, 1886., Poem (Page 109)
  - 55. Matthews, James Brander, 1852-1929 (Page 110, 111)
    - to Mr. Palmer, Sept. 20, 1890., A.L.S.
    - June 1914., A.N.S.
  - 56. Hamburg, Mark (Page 112)
    - to Mrs. Bishop, Sept. 13, A.L.S.
  - 57. Harvey, Sir John Martin, 1863-1944 (Page 113)
    - to H. C. Hilgate, Sept. 25, 1908., T.L.S.
  - 58. Alexander, Sir George, 1858-1918 (Page 115)
    - to Miss Waddell, [Feb. 6, 1906]and cvr., A.L.S.
  - 59. Granville-Barker, Harley, 1877- (Page 121)
    - to [Richard] Bennett, Apr. 9, A.L.S.
  - 60. Belasco, David, 1859-1931 (Page 123)
    - to Felton Elkins, May 22, 1925., T.L.S.
  - 61. Brieux, [Eugéne], 1858-1932 (Page 125)
    - in French to [Richard Bennett], May 6, 1917, A.L.S.
  - 62. Bates, Blanche (Mrs. George Creel), 1873-1941 (Page 126, 129)
    - to Felton Elkins, 1921 & n.d.,one cvr., 4 A.L.S.
  - 63. [Bennett, Richard?], 1872-1944 (Page 130)
    - to Felton Elkins, [Mar., 23 1920],signed Dick, with cover., A.L.S.
  - 64. Bennett, Richard, 1872-1944 (Page 131)
    - to Felton Elkins, Nov. 18, 1919, T.L.S.
  - 65. Cobb, Irvin S., 1876-1944 (Page 132)
    - to Felton Elkins, May 22, A.L.S.
  - 66. Copeland, C. T. (Page 133)
    - fragment, n.d., T.L.S.
  - 67. Chambers, Charles Hadden, 1860-1921 (Page 134, 135)
    - to Felton Elkins, [Nov., 1919-n.d.], 3 A.L.S.
  - 68. du Maurier, Sir Gerald, 1873-1934 (Page 136)
    - to F. Elkins, Jun. 15,with cover., A.L.S.
  - 69. Drew, John, 1853-1927 (Page 137)
    - to F. Elkins, Oct. 28, 1913., A.L.S.
  - 70. Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933 (Page 140-143)
    - to F. Elkins, Mar. 24, [1912], Jun. 29, 1912with cover, Apr. 13, 1912., 3 A.L.S.
  - 71. Hopwood, Avery, 1882-1928 (Page 144, 145)
    - to F. Elkins, n.d., A.L.S.
  - 72. Marbury, Elizabeth (Page 147)
    - to F. Elkins, [Apr. 11, 1925], A.L.S.
  - 73. Miller, Henry (Page 148, Page 149)
    - Telegram to F. Elkins, Mar. 17, 1923
    - [to F. Elkins, n.d., A.L.S.
  - 74. Maude, Cyril, 1862- (Othertype VERY LARGE BOX, Page 150-151)
    - T.N.S. and 4 to F. Elkins, n.d., A.L.S.
  - 75. O'Neill, Eugene, 1888- (Page 152-157)
    - to F. Elkins, 1919, 1924 and n.d., 3 A.L.S. L.S. and 2; one cover.
  - 76. Roosevelt, Theodore Autograph (Page 159)
  - 77. Sheldon, Edward Brewster, 1886-1946 (Page 160-165)
    - 2 and 5 tels (1 holograph) to F. Elkins. n.d., 1918, 1923 and [1915],2 signed Ned, A.L.S.
  - 78. Tempest, [Marie] (Page 160)
    - Tel. to F. Elkins, Sept. 27, 1921
  - 79. Titherade, Madge (Page 167)
    - to F. Elkins, Apr. 19, A.L.S.
  - 80. Alcazar Theatre Program, 1903with signatures of players (Page 171)
  - 81. Panteleieff, Max, holograph copy of program (Page 180)
  - 82. Panteleieff, Consuelo Closs, signed photo (Page 181)
  - 83. Panteleieff, Mary (Page 181)
    - to F. Elkins, [1926],not mounted., 2 A.L.S.
- COLLECTION OF CLIPPINGS CONCERNING PEOPLE AND THINGS LITERARY (Volume 2 (Vol.))
  - 1. First Editions signed by Elsie B. Stone., Typed poem
  - 2. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Mrs. Kate Felton Nielson., T.L.S.
  - 3. Nathan Van Patten to Mrs. Kate Felton Nielson., T.L.S.
  - 4. O. W. Holmes to Mr. Sanborn., Typed copy
  - 5. Henry W. Longfellow to unknown., Typed copy
- SCRAPBOOK OF CONCERT AND OPERA PROGRAMS, 1919-1927 (Volume 3 (Vol.))
  Art gallery program, clippings on performers, ballet programs, copies of Symphony Society Bulletin (N.Y.) for San Francisco seasons, 1919-27, and New York and Philadelphia season 1922-23.
- SCRAPBOOK OF THEATER PROGRAMS, 1919-1924 (Volume 4 (Vol.))
  Both stage and film productions for San Francisco seasons, 1919-21 and 1923-24 and New York season, 1922-23.
- THEATRE PROGRAMME BOOK, 1882-1896 (Volume 5 (Vol.), Page p. 30)
  Clippings, photos, concert, theater and opera programs from New York, Philadelphia, Washington, D. C., San Francisco, Menlo Park, Chicago, Boston, Syracuse, Buffalo, St. Louis, Frankfurt a. M., Paris, London, Birmingham, Liverpool and Brighton. A.N.S. from E. N. Palmer (Emma Nevada) to Mrs. Elkins, n.d. (ca. 1885),
- Kate Felton Elkins Collection, Fe 125
  Scrapbooks on musical, theatrical and literary subjects
  - 1. Dramatics - bound leather book containing autograph letters or signed letters by many persons in the theater in the 19th and early 20th century Also old playbills, prints, printed articles, and photographs., ML 410 F 757
    (for item by item of letters & autographs - draft of list of contents for Fe 124)
  - 4. Scrapbook of Theater Programs 1919-1924for both stage and film productions, PN 2226 S43
  - 3. Scrapbook of Concert and Opera Programs 1919-1927,art gallery program clips on performers, ballet programs copies of symphony Society Bulletin, N.Y. etc., ML 40 A 1 S 43
  - 2. Collection of Clippings concerning People and Things Literary (and miscellany signed), P N 771 E 44
    - 1. First Editions by Elsie B. Stene, Typed poem
    - 2. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Mrs. Kate Felton Neilson, TLS
    - 3. Natuan Van Patten to Kate Felton Nielson, T.L.S.
    - 4. O.W. Holmes to Mr. Sanborn, typed copy
    - 5. Henry W. Long Fellow to?, typed copy
  - 5. Theatre Programme Book, PN2226 T37 f
- Dramatic
  - Elizabeth - print from a painting by Isaac Oliver (Page p. 3)
  - Elizabeth portrait proof print before letters by W. T. Walker 1791 (Page p. 4)
  - Francis Bacon French print. Several Paris chez E. Desrochers (Page p. 5)
  - The Room in Which Shakspeare Was Born. print. T. G. Flowers. Edinburgh. pub by E. Adams (Page p. 7)
  - Ben jonson. print & biographical sketch [Hontueret?] [pint.].; Audinet, sculp; pub by Harrison & [?] May 1, 1794 (Page p. 8)
  - Ben Jonson. Engraved by E. Scriven from a picture in the possession of Mr. Knight. pub. by Charles Knight (Page p. 9)
  - Abraham Cowley. Mary Beale pint.; R. Godfrey s. pub Nov. 1, 1776by F. Blyth. (Page p. 10)
  - Colley Cibber. [1767]Vanloo pinx J. S. Miller Sc. (Page p. 11)
  - Theatre Royal, Covent Garden broadside Feb 13, 1790.The Dramatist etc (Page p. 12)
  - Margaret Woffington as Sir Harry Wildair. Wm. Hogarth, pinxt, N.Y. Photogravure Co. (Page 13)
  - Mr. Garrick as Periauder. Roberts del., Wilsosculp. (Page 14)
  - Page from Stars of the Stage (pp.21 & 22) re: Garrick (Page p. 15)
  - Theatre Royal. broadside July 30, 1807,Tobin's The Curfew etc. (Page p. 16)
  - Charles Kemble page from a book with portrait and biographical sketch (Page p. 21)
  - Fanny Kemble painted by T. Sally, engraved by J. Cheney
  - Theatre Royal, Hay-Market, broadside June 28, 1831 As You Like It etc. (Page p. 22)
  - Theatre Royal, Drury Lane. broadside May 15, 1837,Mme. Schroeder Devrient Fidelio etc. (Page p. 23)
  - Theatre Royal, Liverpool broadside Mar. 23, 1841,Wallach in Pizarro etc. (Page p. 24)
  - Sir Walter Scott, Bart, Sir T. Lawrence piuxt., J. Horsburgh sculpt., pub. Gebbie & Barrie. (Page p. 25)
  - Theatre-Royal Liverpool broadside Mar. 31, 1841Wallask in Rent Day etc. (Page p. 27)
  - Gabriel Ravel, clipping w/portrait (Page p. 28)
  - Edwin Booth as Hamlet p. from a book w/portrait (Page p. 30)
  - Edwin Thomas Booth page from book w/biographical sketch & 3 illustrations (Page p. 31)
  - Edwin Books portrait with facsimile signature John Wilson & Co. Publrs. N.Y. (Page p. 32)
  - Lawrence Barrett, clip. biographical (Page p. 34)
  - Lawrence Barrett as Count Lauciotto page from book (Page p. 35)
  - John E. McCullough, photograph (Page p. 40)
  - John E. McCullough, biographical clip (Page p. 41)
  - Mrs Keane, photograph (Page p. 45)
  - Charles Keane, photograph
  - Fords Theatre copy of broadside for Apr 14, 1865 Our American Cousin Lincoln (Page p. 46)
  - E. A. Southern as Lord Dundreary in Our America Cousin illustrated article. (Page p. 46)
  - [E. A. Southern], photograph (Page p. 47)
  - Fanny Davenport, photo (Page p. 49)
  - Mrs. Bishop, photo
  - Mrs. Bowers, photo
  - Joseph Jefferson as Rip Van Winckle, illustrated dip (Page p. 50)
  - Joseph Jefferson as Newman Noggs, engraved by R.G. Tietze from photo formerly owned by John Broughan, lent by Peter [Gilecy?], [copy of engraving] (Page p. 51)
  - Henry Irving as Hamlet, Illus'd clip (Page p. 52)
  - Henry Irving big sketch for Stars of the Stage (Page p. 53)
  - Mrs. G. H. Gilbert big sketch for Stars of the Stage
  - Ellen Terry big. clip co/photo as Letitia Hardy (Page p. 54)
  - Miss Ellen Terry as Partia, clip, illus. (Page p. 55)
  - Madam Modjeslca as Queen Mary, clip a biographical clip (Page p. 57)
  - [John Drew? & Ada Rehan?], photo (Page p. 58)
  - Ada Rehan as Katharina, clip (Page p. 59)
  - John Drew as Patrucio, clip
  - Arch Street Theatre, Philadelphia., clipped illus. (Page p. 68)
  - Wheatley's Arch St. Theatre broadside July 2 `56 Gold etc. (Page p. 69)
  - Miss Neilson as Juliet (Page p. 70)
  - Lilean Adelaide Neilson photo on sheet music cover (Page p. 71)
  - Dramatic Affairs clip from The Californian Sept. 21, 1867 (Page p. 74)
  - The Californian clips Dramatic Mention 3/18/63 Amusements Musical 6/9 1866 (Page p. 75)
  - Private Dispatches song words pub. by Bell & Company, S.F. (Page p. 76)
  - Kole Oil Tommy Song Words pub. by T.C. Boyd. S.F. (Page p. 77)
  - Ben Bolt Song words pub. by Bell & Company
  - Lotta M. Crabtree, photo (Page 78)
  - [unk], Illus. clip (Page 79)
  - Annie Pixley as M'liss, illus. clip (Page p. 81)
  - Adelena Patti, photo (Page p. 83)
  - Interieur du Théâtre de la Scala à Milan Sidole dess, gravé par L. Cherbuin ed. - Ferd. Astoria et File, Milan (Page p. 85)
  - Mlle. Georges. colored reproductions of drawing by J. Champagne (Page p. 86)
  - The Great Excitement Galup by Piette Laroche. ad poster or cover of sheet music (Page p. 87)
  - Johnston Forbes-Robertson, photo (Page p. 94)
  - Maude Adams, photo (Page p. 96)
  - Maude Adams, signed photo (Page p. 97)
  - Maude Adams, signed photo; Maude Adams. ribbon of the Legion of Honor which she wore in a play
  - Maxime Elliott, signed photo (Page p. 101)
  - Theodore Roosevelt, photo (Page p. 159)
  - Empire Theatre, N. Y. June 9-14, 1924program She Steeps to Conquer (Page p. 169)
  - Alcazar Theatre, S.F. May 18-31, 1903signed program of Heartsease (Page P. 171)
  - [Ruta Chatterton?] - announcement of performance (Page P. 172)
  - Columbia Theatre, S.F. program Sept. 27, 30, 1927Ruta Chatterton presents Into the Sunlight w/ Henry Miller, Blanche Bates, etc. (Page P. 173)
  - Columbia Theatre, clips re: above from Bulletin & Journal (Page P. 174)
  - Greenwich Village Theatre program A.W.O.L. (Page P. 175)
  - Mariarden, Peterborough, N.H. program The Imperfect 36 (Page P. 176)
  - California Theatre 1863Free Public Library. Bush St. above Kearney. Photo enlargement (Page P. 179)